Burns & Burns Records, 1871-1910
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Burns & Burns Records, 1871-1910
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms94-032
2 boxes; 2.0 cu. ft.
The collection consists of the office records of Burns & Burns, Attorneys at Law, of Lebanon, Virginia. The records consist of case files, legal briefs, correspondence, circuit court petitions, and collection notices.
Burns & Burns, Attorneys at Law
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Burns & Burns Records were purchased by Special Collections in 1994.
Historical Information
The collection consists of the office records of Burns & Burns, Attorneys at Law, of Lebanon, Virginia. The records begin as those of Burns & Ayers until approximately 1900, when the firm changed its name to Burns & Burns and was headed by William E. Burns.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of the office records of Burns & Burns, Attorneys at Law, of Lebanon, Virginia. The records begin as those of Burns & Ayers until approximately 1900, when the firm changed its name to Burns & Burns and was headed by William E. Burns. The records consist of case files, legal briefs, correspondence, circuit court petitions, and collection notices. Corporate clients include the Norfolk & Western Railway Company, Clinch Valley Coal & Iron Company, the Long Pole Lumber Company, the Bassett Jewelry Company, and the Illinois Sewing Machine Company, among others. The firm also defended several people against the Commonwealth of Virginia in murder trials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Elizabeth Samples vs. Stuart Land & Cattle Company, land dower dispute, 1871-1897. (Box-folder 1:1)
- W.A. Stewart vs. A.S. Carter, land dispute, 1891-1895. (Box-folder 1:2)
- H.C. Stuart vs. J.H. Tow, 1892-1898. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Miscellaneous collection correspondence, 1892-1918. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia at Wytheville, James S. Helton vs. P.L. Johnson, 1893. (Box-folder 1:5)
- R. Stinson & Son vs. Harris & Stinson, 1893-1896. (Box-folder 1:6)
- L.B. Self vs. A.K. Couch, 1893-1898. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Holland addition (Coeburn Land & Improvement Co.), 1893-1905. (Box-folder 1:8)
- W.H. Barrow vs. C.W. Hunt, 1894. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Brown vs. B.J. Wysor, 1894. (Box-folder 1:10)
- James S. Helton vs. P.L. Johnson, 1894 (Box-folder 1:11)
- P.L. Johnson vs. L. Finney, 1894. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Pocahontas Inn vs. Samuel Ashton Jr., 1894. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Tucker & Co. vs. Harris and Stinson, 1894. (Box-folder 1:14)
- H.C. Stuart vs. Sue G. Hancock, estate settlement, 1894-1895. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. W.N. Rensch, 1894-1896. (Box-folder 1:16)
- Campbell vs. Carter's heirs, 1894-1896. (Box-folder 1:17)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. John Wilson, felony, 1895. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Dr. Harter Medicine Co. vs. L.J. Johnson, 1895. (Box-folder 1:19)
- Mary E. Stinson vs. Margaret Hargis, estate settlement, 1895-1896. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Tucker & Co. vs. H.C. Davis, 1895-1896. (Box-folder 1:21)
- Powers, Little & Co. vs. J.H. Humphreys, 1895-1897. (Box-folder 1:22)
- J.T. Puckett vs. D. Getzendanner, 1895-1898. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Alfred Goff et al, 1896. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Huntsman Bros. & Co. vs. J.B. Fuller, 1896. (Box-folder 1:25)
- Elizabeth Rasnick vs. Reuben Banner, 1896. (Box-folder 1:26)
- J.M. Robinson Norton & Co. vs J.T. Kendrick & Co., 1896. (Box-folder 1:27)
- Tucker & Co. vs. Honaker Produce & Supply, 1896. (Box-folder 1:28)
- Debt collections against T.K. Wallace, 1896-1899. (Box-folder 1:29)
- Miscellaneous postcards, 1896-1918. (Box-folder 1:30)
- Miscellaneous envelopes, 1896-1924. (Box-folder 1:31)
- The Fidelity Insurance, Trust Safe & Deposit Co. vs. Norfolk & Western Railroad Co., 1897. (Box-folder 1:32)
- Norfolk & Western Railway and Lebanon & Cleveland Telephone papers concerning placement of telephone equipment on N & W property, 1897. (Box-folder 1:33)
- M.L. Ogburn & Co. vs. J.J. Dickenson, 1897. (Box-folder 1:34)
- The Russell College vs. A.F. Hunt, 1897. (Box-folder 1:35)
- The Russell College vs. H. Sawyers, 1897. (Box-folder 1:36)
- H.A. Shoemaker vs. James S. Helton and V.B. Meade, 1897. (Box-folder 1:37)
- Martha Ann Street vs. Wilson et al, land deed, 1897. (Box-folder 1:38)
- The Piano Manufacturing Co. vs. William E. Fields, 1898. (Box-folder 1:39)
- Jackson, Oglesby & Co. vs. H.D. Lockhart & Co., 1898-1899. (Box-folder 1:40)
- Pearre Bros. & Co. vs. C.H. Compton & Co., 1898-1899. (Box-folder 1:41)
- Letters of Jane Collins, Jack Hardin, C.E. Stafford and others concerning Burns & Ayers interest in land and timber, 1898-1900. (Box-folder 1:42)
- Pearre Bros. & Co. vs. C.H. Compton & Co., 1898-1900. (Box-folder 1:43)
- J.H. Meade vs. M.V. Fletcher, 1898-1903. (Box-folder 1:44)
- Receipt for writ tax in Burns & Ayers vs. J.B. Fugate, 1900. (Box-folder 1:45)
- Letter concerning Howard vs. N & W Railway, 1900. (Box-folder 1:46)
- F.R. Penn Tobacco Co. vs. H.F. Garrett & Co., 1900. (Box-folder 1:47)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Taylor Horton and Henry Horton, 1900-1901. (Box-folder 1:48)
- Ashbrook and Thomas vs. A.J. Kaufhold, 1900-1905. (Box-folder 1:49)
- Powers, Little & Co. vs. C. Wallace, 1901-1902. (Box-folder 1:50)
- Powers, Little & Co. vs. T.K. Wallace & Son, 1901-1902. (Box-folder 1:51)
- Fee bills for J.B. Ashbrook, 1901-1904. (Box-folder 1:52)
- C.S. and J.H. Bradshaw vs. G.C. Gose, Administrator, 1902. (Box-folder 1:53)
- H.H. Dickenson & Son vs. H.B. Ferguson, 1902-1904. (Box-folder 1:54)
- Benjamin Dye vs. J.C. Artrip, 1902-1907. (Box-folder 1:55)
- G.W. Quarles & Co. vs. J.E. Monk, 1903. (Box-folder 1:56)
- Cyrus Blankenship vs. W.M. Ritter Lumber Co., 1903. (Box-folder 1:57)
- W.E. Burns correspondence concerning Robert Cross loan with the Princeton Banking Co., 1903. (Box-folder 1:58)
- Clinch Valley Barytes Co. Vs. J. McGlothins heirs, 1903. (Box-folder 1:59)
- A. Combs vs. R. Clark, 1903. (Box-folder 1:60)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Frank A. Smith, 1903. (Box-folder 1:61)
- Wolford Bros. Vs. Barney Thompson, 1903. (Box-folder 1:62)
- Interstate Coal & Iron Co. and Clinch Valley Coal & Iron Co. vs. John Cook's heirs (also, see same vs. John Warder's heirs), 1903-1905. (Box-folder 1:63)
- Interstate Coal & Iron Co. and Clinch Valley Coal & Iron Co. vs. John Warder's heirs (also, see same vs. John Cook's heirs), 1903-1906. (Box-folder 1:64)
- Incorporation of Swords Creek Coal and Coke Co. 1903-1906. (Box-folder 1:65)
- John W. Ball vs. Clinch Valley Barytes Co., 1903-1908. (Box-folder 1:66)
- Mary E. Counts vs. Lot Counts, et al, 1903-1909. (Box-folder 1:67)
- J.W. Bastic vs. John C. Fugate, debt, 1904. (Box-folder 1:68)
- McCue & Wright Milling Co. vs. J.H. Shoemaker, 1904. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Office of W.W. Bird, commissioner of Lebanon, VA, depositions concerning S.M. McEwen vs. Dawson Coal & Coke, 1904. (Box-folder 2:2)
- W.L. Dennis vs. Parris Charles, 1904. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Elk Garden Mercantile Co. vs. C.J. Dickenson, 1904. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Enterprise Foundry Co. vs. Robinson and Sharmaker, 1904. (Box-folder 2:5)
- H.C. Ketron vs. Geo W.H. Gilmer, partition, 1904. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Wilson Litton vs. Mary Litton, settlement of Salomon Litton's estate, 1904. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Contract for Long Pole Lumber Co. and William H. Haire, 1904. (Box-folder 2:8)
- McCue & Wright Milling Co. vs. J.E. Monk, 1904. (Box-folder 2:9)
- McEwen depositions concerning suit against Dawson Coal & Coke, 1904. (Box-folder 2:10)
- S.N. Johnson vs. Norfolk & Western Railway Co., 1904. (Box-folder 2:11)
- H.C. Smith letter to Burns & Burns, 1904. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Thompson & Crockett vs. Norfolk and Western Railway Co., 1904. (Box-folder 2:13)
- In re Kilgore's direct index and reference to deed books, 1904. (Box-folder 2:14)
- Isaac Eberly vs. Paris Charles, 1904. (Box-folder 2:15)
- Flat Top Grocery Co. vs. J.H. Shoemaker, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:16)
- Myrtle Harris vs. Charlie Harris, partition, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:17)
- William Honaker vs. Isaac Honaker, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:18)
- W.A. Scott & Co. vs. G.E. Burnett, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:19)
- John N. Watkins vs. W.J. Williamson, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:20)
- M.D. Wells vs. T.K. Wallace & Sons, 1904-1905. (Box-folder 2:21)
- R.E. Hawley vs. H.H. Aston, 1904-1909. (Box-folder 2:22)
- J.B. Bradshaw vs. Cosby Bradshaw, suit to partition land, 1905. (Box-folder 2:23)
- Bluefield Furniture Co. vs. G.E. Burnett, 1905. (Box-folder 2:24)
- L. Finney vs. Long Pole Lumber Co., 1905. (Box-folder 2:25)
- Morgan Justus vs. W.M. Ritter Lumber Co., 1905. (Box-folder 2:26)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Joe Doston, 1905. (Box-folder 2:27)
- Bluefield Hardware Co. vs. Brown & Cyphers, 1905. (Box-folder 2:28)
- G.W. Price vs. Norfolk and Western Railway Co., 1905. (Box-folder 2:29)
- Wilbur Stock Food Co. vs. J.T. Brattin, 1905. (Box-folder 2:30)
- Spencer Tracy Co. vs. Banner Co., 1905. (Box-folder 2:31)
- Sweer, Orr Co. vs. D. Banner, 1905. (Box-folder 2:32)
- Bluefield Furniture Co. vs. M.L. Barrett, 1905. (Box-folder 2:33)
- A.C. Fowler vs. Long Pole Lumber Co., 1905-1906. (Box-folder 2:34)
- A. D. Shoemaker vs. Gardner Barytes, 1905-1906. (Box-folder 2:35)
- Flanders vs. Salyer Bros., 1905-1906. (Box-folder 2:36)
- William Nash and Fullen Nash vs. Yellow Poplar Lumber Co., Excelsior Coal & Lumber Co., Russell Fork Coal & Lumber Co., and Virginia Trust Co., 1905-1910. (Box-folder 2:37)
- Elliot vs. Elliot, estate settlement, 1906. (Box-folder 2:38)
- Douglas H. Gordon vs. R.G. Watkins, estate settlement, 1906. (Box-folder 2:39)
- Guggenheimer & Co. vs. Banner & House, 1906. (Box-folder 2:40)
- Thomas McCloud vs. Clinch Valley Barytes Co., contract dispute, 1906. (Box-folder 2:41)
- The Red Cross Supply Co. vs. Mrs. Amanda Collins, 1906. (Box-folder 2:42)
- J.C. Smith correspondence to C.C. Burns concerning Counts vs. Counts, 1906. (Box-folder 2:43)
- Abbey Wilson and Robert Coleman vs. Abel McFaddin and J.C. Pipper, 1906. (Box-folder 2:44)
- A.C. Fowler vs. Hutchinson Lumber & Manufacturing Co., 1906-1907. (Box-folder 2:45)
- Bassett Jewelry Co. vs. L.L. Bays & Sons, 1906-1907. (Box-folder 2:46)
- Illinois Sewing Machine Co. vs. A.D. Stewart & Co., 1906-1908. (Box-folder 2:47)
- J.I. Hunt vs. J.H. Chandler, 1906-1908. (Box-folder 2:48)
- Travelers Insurance Co. vs. Clinch Valley Baryter Co., 1906-1909. (Box-folder 2:49)
- Thomas, Andrews & Co. vs. Salyer Bros., 1907. (Box-folder 2:50)
- Baltimore Bargain House vs. Perry Honaker & Co., 1908. (Box-folder 2:51)
- Bowser & Co. vs. A.L. Grizzle, 1908. (Box-folder 2:52)
- Guggenheimer & Co. vs. O'Keita Planning Mill Co., 1908. (Box-folder 2:53)
- Illinois Sewing Machine Co. vs. A.L. Grizzle, 1908. (Box-folder 2:54)
- Stebbins Specialty Co. vs. T. R. Robinson, 1908-1909. (Box-folder 2:55)
- O.H. Viall vs. Boyd & Alderson, 1908-1909. (Box-folder 2:56)
- E.R. Boyd note to C.C. Burns concerning Illinois Sewing Machine Co. vs. Henry Ratliff, 1909. (Box-folder 2:57)
- Correspondence between Robertson, Burns, and Morison concerning McEwen vs. Dawson Coal & Coke Co., 1910. (Box-folder 2:58)
- Ashbrook & Thomas vs. A.J. Kaufhold. (Box-folder 2:59)
- Sarah Barton vs. Jasper Cook's heirs. (Box-folder 2:60)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. David Ball and Cornelius Ball. (Box-folder 2:61)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. George Cook. (Box-folder 2:62)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Lindsay Thompson and Gregory Burnett. (Box-folder 2:63)
- Commonwealth of Virginia vs. Wiley Oquinn. (Box-folder 2:64)
- Charles Johnson vs. James L Smith and wife, ejectment. (Box-folder 2:65)
- Russell County Circuit Court depositions for S.M. McEwen vs. Dawson Coal & Coke Co. (Box-folder 2:66)
- Dr. J.M. Taulbee vs. Russell County. (Box-folder 2:67)
- Abstract title of George A. Warder, et al. (Box-folder 2:68)
- Songs and memoriam by L.A. Killion written about his parents. Deed to L. Killion included. (Box-folder 2:69)